* Search
    
* Health topics

Most popular today

* [COVID-19](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/covid-19/) (550)
* [Vaccines](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/vaccines/) (132)
* [Opioids](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/opioids/) (42)
* [Cancer](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/cancer/) (145)
* [Addiction](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/addiction/) (154)
* [Racism](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/racism/) (36)
* [Alcohol](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/alcohol/) (23)
* [Infectious Disease](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/infectious-disease/) (652)
* [Marijuana](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/marijuana/) (22)
* [Tobacco](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/tobacco/) (20)
* [Aging](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/aging/) (196)
* [Dementia](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/dementia/) (40)
* [Long-Term Care](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/long-term-care/) (78)
* [Children and Youth](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/children-and-youth/) (265)
* [Education](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/education/) (344)
* [Medical Education](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/medical-education/) (175)
* [Depression](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/depression/) (25)
* [Misinformation](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/misinformation/) (86)
* [Nursing](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/nursing/) (27)
* [End of Life](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/end-of-life/) (124)
* [In Memoriam](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/in-memoriam/) (5)
* [MAiD](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/maid/) (30)
* [Environment](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/environment/) (64)
* [Climate Change](https://healthydebate.ca/topic/climate-change/) (32)

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective Date 20 February, 2021.

### 1\. Introduction

HealthyDebate.ca, (“We”, “Us”, “Our”) is a website (“Site”) owned and operated by Healthy Debate, a Not-for-Profit organization. As a reader, sharer of content or contributor, You are referred to herein as (“You”, “Your”, “User(s)”). The collection, use and disclosure of Your personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) will be governed under the terms of this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

By using this Site, You consent to the collection, use and disclosure of Your Personal Information under the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We may change this policy without notice from time to time to reflect changes in legal or regulatory obligations. Your continued use of this site means that You accept those changes. The date of the most recent version of these Terms is noted above as its Effective Date. We welcome You to check back at any time to make sure You are aware of current Terms. Healthy Debate does not and will not accept any other Terms.

### 2\. How and what we collect

We collect Personal Information from:

* You directly, when You:
    * make a comment or guest post and You provide Your name, email address and photo;
    * contact Us via email, mail or telephone.
* Your computer, through analytics software (Cookies) installed on our Site that records:
    * Your IP address;
    * Your preferences and interests.

We retain Your Personal Information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected and to comply with applicable laws.

### 3\. When We disclose Your Personal Information.

We reserve the right to disclose Personal Information to a third party if a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order legally requires or authorizes us to do so and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect Your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

### 4\. Security, retention and storage of Personal Information

We take all reasonable steps to protect Your privacy and Your personal information. We do not accept any responsibility for unauthorized access, theft or loss of Personal Information beyond our reasonable control. Further, please note that communications over the Internet, such as emails, are not secure unless they are encrypted.

We are committed to ensuring that Your Personal Information is secure. In order to prevent loss, theft and unauthorized access, copying, use, modification or disclosure, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and help secure the Personal Information we collect.

### 5\. Links to other websites

Our Sites may contain links to other websites of interest. Once You leave our Site, You should note that we do not have any control over that other website and the privacy practices of other websites.

### 6\. Cookies

HealthyDebate.ca may use cookies to help improve the content within our site by helping us understand how visitors use and how many times the same visitor will revisit our site. You can choose to have Your computer warn You each time a cookie is being sent or You can choose to turn off all cookies. This can be done through Your browser. Each browser is a little different, so look at Your browser’s help menu to learn the correct way to modify Your cookie acceptance. If You turn cookies off, You won’t have access to many features provided by various websites, including personalized login sessions and the storage of Your personal preferences.

### 7\. Controlling Your Personal Information

You may choose to restrict the collection, use or disclosure of Your Personal Information in the following ways:

If You wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use Your name and email address to send the newsletter to You. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter by contacting us. If You have left comments or a Guest Post on our Site, that information may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. If You wish to remove any of Your previously submitted information, contact Us and it will be removed. If we are unable to do so, we will let You know and why.

### 8\. Contact us

If You have any queries about our processing or use of Your Personal Information or wish to modify or correct or delete Your Personal Information, You should write, in the first instance to our Privacy Officer, Seema Marwaha at [seema@healthydebate.ca](mailto:seema@healthydebate.ca)

### 9\. Privacy Commissioner of Canada

If You want to learn more about Your rights regarding Your Personal Information, You may contact the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada at 1-800-282-1376 or visit their website at [http://www.priv.gc.ca/index\_e.asp](http://www.priv.gc.ca/index_e.asp).

### 10\. Information about third party analytics and cookie blocking

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of Cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

Donate to Healthy Debate
------------------------

Your support allows us to publish journalism about healthcare in Canada that is free to read and free to republish. Donations are tax-deductible.

Join the mailing list
---------------------

Sign up below to receive our newsletter every Thursday morning.

* First name\*
    
* Last name\*
    
* Email address\*

Δ

You can republish our articles online or in print for free. Read more.
